* Hoạt động nào sau đây không tính timeboxed (hạn, mốc hoàn thành)?

Select one:
a. Sprint Retrospective
b. Sprint
c. Sprint Review

Đáp án d. Làm mịn Product Backlog

e. Daily Scrum

------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
* Một team là cross-functional (đa chức năng) là như nào?

Đáp án a. Đội phát triển có đủ các kỹ năng cần thiết để hoàn thành công việc được giao

Cross-Functional Scrum Teams are the teams having all the necessary skills and proficiency within the team to accomplish their work. These teams do not rely on anyone outside the team for completing the work items.
Thus, the Scrum Team is a very creative amalgamation of different skills required to complete the entire work item. Each team member may not necessarily have all the skills required to build the product but is competent in his/her area of expertise.
Having said that, the team member need not be cross-functional but the team as a whole has to be.

b. Đội phát triển bao gồm các lập trình viên và các tester
c. Lập trình viên có thể tạo các testcase và thực thi chúng.
d. Đội phát triển có thể hợp tác với các đội khác
e. Mỗi thành viên trong đội phải đa năng

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
* Điều gì xảy ra nếu các items trong Sprint không hoàn thành?

Select one:

Đáp án a. Sprint kết thúc với các items đã xong

In a case where the team is unable to complete all the Sprint Backlog items, nothing happens. The Sprint ends on the stipulated date with the completed items. The Development Team demonstrates the completed items in the Sprint Review meeting.
The uncompleted items are moved back to the Product Backlog and are again prioritized from there.
b. Những items không hoàn thành bị loại khỏi Project Backlog
c. Khởi động sprint tiếp theo cho các items chưa hoàn thành
d. Điều chỉnh Sprint
e. Sprint bị hủy

--------------------------------------------------------------------------
* Trong Scrum, khi nào 1 Sprint kết thúc?

Select one:
a. Khi Product Owner bảo kết thúc
b. Khi mọi items trong Sprint Backlog được hoàn thành
c. Khi bước final testing được hoàn thành

Đáp án: d. Khi thời gian của Sprint đã hết.
All the Sprint activities are time boxed including Sprint. Unlike other Sprint activities, Sprint can neither be extended nor shortened.
If for instance, all the items of a Sprint are not completed, the Sprint is still marked over and the remaining item(s) is moved to the Product Backlog from where it can be scheduled to any of the subsequent sprint based on the revised priority. Similarly, the Sprint can never be shortened.
If all the Sprint items are completed before time, the development team is free to pull in the top Product Backlog items and start the development.

e. Khi mọi task trong Sprint Backlog được hoàn thành

-------------------------------------------------------------------------
